A Crime is a crime film directed by Manuel Pradal.
Vincent's life is on hold until he finds his wife's killer.
Alice, his neighbor, is convinced she can make him happy.
She decides to invent a culprit, so that Vincent can
find revenge and leave the past behind.
But there is no ideal culprit and no perfect crime.
Roger Culkin, played by Harvey Keitel.
Alice Parker, played by Emmanuelle Béart.
Vincent Harris, played by Norman Reedus.
Bill, played by Joe Grifasi.
Sophie, played by Lily Rabe.
Ashley, played by Kim Director.
Crime film is a film belonging to the crime fiction genre.
Films of this genre generally involve various aspects of crime.
Stylistically, the genre may overlap and combine with many other genres, such as drama or gangster film, but also
include comedy, and, in turn, is divided into many sub-genres, such as mystery, suspense, or noir.
Screenwriter and scholar Eric R.
Williams identified crime film as one of eleven super-genres in his Screenwriters Taxonomy,
claiming that all feature-length narrative films can be classified by these super-genres.
The other ten super-genres are action, fantasy, horror, romance, science
fiction, slice of life, sports, thriller, war and western.
Williams identifies drama in a broader category called "film type", mystery and suspense as "macro-genres", and film
noir as a "screenwriter's pathway" explaining that these categories are additive rather than exclusionary.
Chinatown would be an example of a film that is a drama (film type) crime film
(super-genre) that is also a noir (pathway) mystery (macro-genre).
The film explores themes of bet, taxi, plan, love triangle, loss of loved one.